shinydevelopment.com 2007-10-03

# Shiny Development :: Privacy Policy

## Privacy

Privacy is of critical importance to us and we take it very seriously, the legal jargon is down below but we work by a few simple principles:

  * We will only collect information from you where it is essential for the running of this web site. Our sign up process typifies this as we ask only for your e-mail address and a name you would like people to know you by.
  * Any other information collected will always be optional and will only ever be asked for to support new features added to the site. For example, if at any point we add the ability to search for other users that live in your area then we will give you the opportunity to enter your area into the site, providing information of this type will always be optional.
  * Any content collected from feeds will only ever be collected from feeds which are available publicly on the internet. Obviously it is going to be impossible to check the contents of every feed we read manually so if you do find any copyrighted or information collected by this site which should not have been available then please let us know.

Below is the privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

## Privacy Policy

Shiny Development Ltd. (" **Shiny Development** ") operates several websites including [shinydevelopment.com](http://shinydevelopment.com/) and [afeeda.com](http://afeeda.com/). It is Shiny Development’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Shiny Development collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Shiny Development’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Shiny Development’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Shiny Development may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Shiny Development also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Shiny Development does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Shiny Development’s websites choose to interact with Shiny Development in ways that require Shiny Development to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Shiny Development gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at [afeeda.com](http://afeeda.com/) to provide an email address and name that they wish to be known by. In each case, Shiny Development collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Shiny Development. Shiny Development does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Shiny Development may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Shiny Development may monitor the most popular accounts on the [afeeda.com](http://afeeda.com/) site. Shiny Development may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Shiny Development does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Shiny Development discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Shiny Development’s behalf or to provide services available at Shiny Development’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Shiny Development’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Shiny Development will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Shiny Development discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Shiny Development believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Shiny Development, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Shiny Development website and have supplied your email address, Shiny Development may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Shiny Development and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Shiny Development takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Shiny Development uses cookies to help Shiny Development identify and track visitors, their usage of Shiny Development website, and their website access preferences. Shiny Development visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Shiny Development’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Shiny Development’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Shiny Development may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Shiny Development’s sole discretion. Shiny Development encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of Shiny Development’s sites after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## Privacy Policy License

We want to say a huge thankyou to the guys over at [Automattic](http://automattic.com/) who make the fabulous [Wordpress](http://wordpress.com/) blogging software for allowing us to copy their privacy policy because they made it available under a [creative commons license](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/) and of course, we are also making this version of their license available under the [same license](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/).

Shiny Development Ltd. is registered in England, Registration Number: 05805802.  
Registered Office: 4 Claridge Court, Lower Kings Road, Berkhamsted, Herts., HP4 2AF.
